Shiva Srinivasan

Sr QA Engineer

Key leader within the dedicated product team experienced in building consensus amongst stakeholders by defining and championing shared product vision of what needs to be built. Talent for conveying clear and compelling narrative and enthusiasm for creating vital functionality. Strong desire for continuous improvement and proven ability to think strategically and act tactically about product quality.

Work History

2015-06 -Current

Sr QA Engineer

Navex Global Inc, Portland, OR

- Act as the liaison for all identity and access management questions for the organization
- Troubleshoot SAML authentication issues while connecting customer's identity provider to authenticate via shibboleth into Navex product
- Design and implement automation framework in the organization
- Being the QA advocate working with product and developers to deliver a quality product
- Be a root cause analysis champion
- Instill culture of Quality in the organization
- Mentor new QA engineers and provide support
- Be the subject matter expert for all identity and access management related queries for business and IT
- Be a root cause analysis champion

2009-01 -2013-01

Application Developer/Conversion Lead

CenturyLink, Vancouver, WA

- Hired to be part of a 10 member team to support client company acquisition to design and develop a conversion process to create quality, usable, secure and scalable systems using agile methodology
- Key contributions
- Built performance optimization solutions reducing

Contact

Phone

720-233-2416

E-mail

sivkumar.s@gmail.com

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/sivkumars

Technical Skills

Jira

Excellent

LACGIII

C#

Very Good

SQL

Very Good

Selenium

Very Good

Cypress

Very Good

Git

Very Good

Team City

Very Good

Jenkins

operation costs by over 50% with \$120K annual savings

- Designed real time reporting tools to track conversion timelines and accuracy
- Spearheaded multiple development projects post conversion driving continuous improvement to processes, systems, work flow and customer responsiveness

2005-01 - Application Developer

Qwest, Denver, CO

- Recruited to develop and maintain a mission critical application
- Responsible to deliver solutions that meet business objectives ensuring adherence to change management processes Key contributions
- Implemented process improvements and designed automated solutions increasing service levels and stability
- Provided CPU reduction solutions on multiple legacy applications saving over \$500k annually
- Reduced the application downtime by optimizing cycle times on nightly batch activities

Education

2009-01

2000-01 - Bachelor Degree: Electronics and Communication Engineering

Accomplishments

- Conceptualized and designed Selenium/c# based automation framework
- Performance optimization that resulted in savings of over \$500k annually



AWS



Javascript



Node.js



React



Expertise

Domain Knowledge



Strategic planning



CI/CD Implementation



Automation knowledge



Training and mentoring



Team Leadership

